Megatron?
威震天？
It seems you've detected the ancient Autobot frequency precisely because it was unearthed.
看来你侦测到的远古汽车人信号是准确的
Well, our backup shouldn't be far behind.
没关系 我们的后援快到了
Without knowing what the Decepticons have exhumed
在不知道霸天虎挖出何物的情况下
I do not think I am willing to wait.
我不愿意再等下去了
Show me.
给我看看
Bring it to me. With utmost care!
拿过来给我 千万小心！
Megatron!
威震天
I cannot allow you to pilfer Autobot relics.
我不允许你窃取汽车人的遗产
Not only are you misinformed, Optimus.
你颠倒了黑白 擎天柱
But I would strongly advise you to lower your weapons.
另外我建议你放下武器
Unless you're in the mood for mutually assured destruction.
除非你想跟我同归于尽
It can't be!
这不可能
The Spark-Extractor.
火种剥离器…
Rather unassuming...
其貌不扬…
yet capable of extracting every Spark within its radius.
却能将它作用范围内的火种尽数吸走
And to think that you led me straight to it, Optimus!
再想到是你引领我得到它的… 擎天柱
Or should I say, Orion Pax did.
噢…或者我应该说 是奥利安・派克斯
You really should have left your Decepticon shield intact.
你真应该好好留着你的霸天虎标志
For you have no idea how useful your code-breaking skills proved to be, during our all too brief time together.
你根本想不到 在我们短暂的蜜月里 你的密码破译技术帮了多大的忙
Soundwave! Send the Groundbridge.
声波 打开环陆桥！
Engage them!
消灭他们！
Bumblebee! Secure the package.
大黄蜂 夺回火种剥离器！
What?!
什么？！
Loop-de-loop, hah.
特技不错嘛 哈
You have some brass bearings, Bumblebee.
你的漆蹭掉啦 大黄蜂
Optimus,
擎天柱
here.
这儿
The source of the ancient frequency we detected.
这是我们探测到的古老频率的来源
An Iacon homing beacon.
是铁堡所用的定位信号
What's an Autobot locator doing on THAT?
这上面为什么会有汽车人的定位器？
The class "A" Decepticon weapons confiscated during the War were sealed within the vaults below Iacon.
战时收缴的霸天虎A级兵器 都被封存在铁堡的地下室里
Where once you worked as an archivist.
就是你曾担任档案员的地方
Iacon was both a cultural center and a stronghold.
铁堡不仅是文化中心 还是战时要塞
Which Megatron raided when Autobot troops were at their nadir.
在汽车人萎靡不振之际 威震天袭击了铁堡
It stands to reason that in anticipation of Iacon being overrun by enemy forces
考虑到铁堡可能沦陷 明智的选择是
these weapons were jettisoned off-world to keep them far from Decepticon reach.
遗弃这些武器 以免落入霸天虎之手
Clearly, the beacon was added as a safety measure
显然 这个定位信号
should the weapons ever be found by the undesired party.
是这些武器被敌方发现时的防范手段
Well, thanks to our hot-shot stunt driver this one is going in our vault.
多亏了我们的特技小子 这一个被我们收回了
Do you think this is the only intel you supplied to Megatron?
你觉得威震天从你那里得到的情报是否只有这些？
Arcee, you are right to ask.
阿尔茜 你问的很对
And I am afraid I... do not remember.
可惜的是我…不记得了
Optimus.
擎天柱
Megatron clearly took advantage of your amnesia.
威震天确实在你失忆时利用了你
But for all we know this Spark-extractor is the extent of it.
但就我们目前所知 只有这个火种剥离器而已
Have you stopped to consider that he might have suggested otherwise merely to plague your thoughts?
他向你暗示还有其他东西 也许只是为了扰乱你的判断
The Spark-extractor was in my grasp!
火种剥离器原本已经到手了！
I should have removed more than that scout's voice-box
当初真应该杀了那个侦察兵
when I had the chance!
而不是只毁掉他的发声器！
Indeed, Soundwave.
没错 声波
We possess two more sets of coordinates which Orion decrypted before departing our ranks.
奥利安走之前留下的坐标还有两个
Let us see what other long lost treasures we might be re-united with.
看看我们还能找到哪些失落已久的宝藏
Yeah. I just picked up the same signal.
是的 我刚刚收到了相同的信号
Could be another homing beacon.
可能又是一个定位信号
Let's rendezvous at the coordinates.
我们在坐标处集合
Silas. Another one's headed to our position.
塞拉斯 另有一个目标在向我们靠近
Estimated arrival - two minutes.
预计…两分钟后抵达
Work briskly.
加快动作
It would appear the signal was a trap.
原来这信号是个陷阱
Better Bumblebee than me.
还好是大黄蜂 不是我
The backup is ahead of schedule.
支援部队提前到了
As luck would have it,
还算走运
so am I.
我干完了
Move out.
收队
Bee!
小蜂！
Who did this? 'Cons?!
这是谁干的？虎子？！
One way to find out. Come on!
我们追上去就知道了 快走！
We rolling’ or not?!
到底走不走啊？！
What do you mean, "you can't"?
你不能？什么意思？
You can fix Bee, can't you?
你一定能修好小蜂的 是吧？
Bumblebee was hit pretty hard.
大黄蜂伤得很重
The stun blast may have fried his T-cog.
震荡射线可能击穿了他的变形齿轮
Is that like a T-bone?
那是一种变形关节吗？
Not exactly.
不完全是
It's the organ that allows us to scan vehicles and transform.
是我们用来扫描车辆和变形的器官
By the Allspark!
火种源在上！
Bumblebee's T-cog isn't damaged.
大黄蜂的变形齿轮不是损坏
It's missing!
而是不见了！
But the Decepticons transform too.
但霸天虎也会变形
Why would they steal that?
他们偷它干什么呢？
Megatron may be known to raise zombies but he is no ghoul.
虽然威震天唤醒过僵尸 但他不会偷器官
If Megatron wasn't behind this then who was?
如果不是威震天干的 会是谁呢？
The ones who cannibalized Breakdown.
把打击拆掉的那群人
And tried to gut me!
他们还想挖出我的心
M.E.C.H.
机械党
And it would appear their knowledge of Cybertronian bio-tech has grown more sophisticated.
看来他们对塞博特恩人的生理机能更精通了
But why would they want Bumblebee's part?
可是 为什么他们要大黄蜂的零件？
Bumblebee, please.
大黄蜂 别
You are not presently equipped to handle this.
以你目前的状况无法胜任
You are mistaken, my friend.
你误会了 我的朋友
I do know what it's like to lose a vital part of oneself.
我当然可以体会失去自身重要部分的痛楚
And, as a result,
也正因此
I know the value of putting one's faith in the strength of those around you.
我更懂得要信赖自己的团队
We vow to do everything in our power to make you whole again.
我们发誓会竭尽全力让你完好如初
And if not, Ratchet can just make you a new...
就算不能 救护车也会为你量身打造一个新…
cog-thing. Right?
…什么齿轮来着？
What did I say?
我说错什么了？
Miko! A T-cog is a bio-mechanism, not a scrap-yard find.
神子! 变形齿轮是生理器官 不是随处可见的旧零件
If it were that easy don't you think
如果像你想的那么容易
I would have replaced Bumblebee's voice-box by now?
我不早就给大黄蜂换上新的发声器了吗？
You are not useless, Bee.
你不是一无是处 小蜂！
All right all right,
好吧 好吧
I say none of us transform until Bumblebee gets his cog back.
我们在大黄蜂的部件找到之前都不变形
Your spark’s in the right place, Bulkhead.
你的心肠很好 隔板
But I don't think now was the time to be limiting ourselves.
但现在可不是自缚手脚的时候
Not with Megatron potentially seeking other Doomsday devices.
尤其是在威震天搜寻可以毁灭世界的装置之时
And I fear not while MECH uses Bumblebee's T-cog
而我还担心机械党在利用大黄蜂的变形齿轮
for their own sinister purpose.
干他们不可告人的勾当
Commence beta-test.
开始第二阶段测试
Installation complete. Commencing scan.
安装成功 开始扫描
Scan successful.
扫描成功
Commencing transformation.
开始变形
You are the ones who turned poor Breakdown into a pitiful science experiment?
就是你们拆了倒霉的打击 并把他变成了可怜的科学实验品？
Didn't learn much from the experience, did you?
没从实验中得到你们想要的吧？
Enough to know where the soft spots are, Decepticon.
这足以知道你的弱点在哪儿了 霸天虎
Oh please. I am no longer affiliated with that entity.
拜托 我已经不属于那个阵营了
Besides, if I were here to avenge the big lug,
再说 如果我是来替大块头寻仇的
you would be screaming for mercy by now.
你早就跪地求饶了
Why are you here?
你来这儿做什么？
To propose an alliance.
来与你们结盟
You see, we have much more in common than you might think.
你看 我们之间的共同点比你想象的要多
And I am not merely referring to our battle scars.
我说的可不只是身上的伤痕
What could I possibly gain from such an arrangement?
那么 这场交易能带给我什么好处？
Insider knowledge.
业内知识
Wise choice.
明智的选择
Now. A T-cog isn't technology. It is biology.
变形齿轮不是技术产品 而是生理器官
Which means it will reject any power source other than energon.
这意味着它排斥一切能源 除了能量体
Go on.
接着说
Energon is the fuel,
能量体就是燃料
the ammunition and the lifeblood of all Cybertronians,
是所有塞博特恩人的弹药和生命源泉
whatever their affiliation.
无论他们是哪个阵营
You and I both want it.
你们和我都想得到它
And currently I lack the means of locating it.
现在我缺少定位它的手段
But once I supply you with the...
不过 只要我向你提供…
particulars of its chemical make-up...
其独特的化学构成
we can utilise your considerable resources
我们就能利用你手头的资源
to devise a means of detecting new deposits.
探测出新的能量矿藏
For us to share.
供我们同享
IF the supply meets M.E.C.H.'s rather significant demand.
前提是这个供应能满足机械党的大量需求
Aah... Intending to build an army, are you?
啊哈…想建立一支军队 是吧？
I am no stranger to ambition.
我对这样的野心可一点都不陌生
Optimus and Bulkhead haven't reported in yet.
擎天柱和隔板暂时还没报告
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
I will let you know the moment I hear something.
有消息我会告诉你的！
Oh for Primus' sake!
看在原始天尊的份上!
Will someone keep him occupied so I can get some work done?!!
谁来给他找点事儿干 好让我专心工作？
Hey, Bee.
嘿 小蜂
How about a videogame?
来把游戏怎么样？
Bad call.
不合时宜
Sorry.
对不起
Hey, no big deal!
嘿 不要紧
That game is lame.
反正这游戏也很烂
What do you say we watch some TV?
看看电视怎么样？
The new Urbana 500. It won't just rock your world.
新款厄巴纳500 不仅仅会震撼你的世界
It will transform it.
还会改变你的世界
Taking the "auto-" out of an Autobot is so not a good thing.
汽车人没了汽车还真是糟糕
Bee, c'mon! You're just as amazing without wheels!
小蜂 别这样 你没轮子也一样耀眼
I mean, speed isn't everything.
我的意思是 速度不代表一切
Personal best, Arcee!
个人最佳纪录 阿尔茜！
You hit 1:20 easy.
轻松打破1分20秒！
Uh-oh.
啊哦…
Bumblebee! Where do you think you're going?
大黄蜂！你去哪儿？
You can't just go for a walk!
你不能就这样随便出去散步！
We are robots in disguise.
我们是隐蔽行动的机器人！
Leaving the base in this form puts you at risk of being seen
离开基地会将你置于险境
and of us being discovered.
而且暴露我们的行踪
You''ll just have to remain in the silo until...
你就呆在这儿 直到…
... yes, Bumblebee. Until I can fix you.
是的 大黄蜂 直到我能把你治好
In you go.
上车 走人
Thanks for the lift home,
谢谢你接我回家
friend of Jack's Mom who is a nurse at... at... the hospital!
杰克的妈妈 在…在医院里做护士
Where are the others?
其他人呢？
Jack's at work.
杰克在打工
Miko's in detention... again.
神子又留堂了
I was expecting Bulkhead.
我还以为隔板会来
Well, I’m sorry to disappoint but he is on watch duty.
好吧 很抱歉让你失望了 不过他在执行任务
You want to ride with the siren on?
想试试警笛开道么？
No, thank you.
不 谢了
This could be it. I'll alert the others.
应该没错 我要通知其他人
I know you and I can handle it,
我知道你能胜任
Bee, but there is no reason to...
不过 小蜂 没理由…
What are you trying to prove?
你想证明什么？
Ratchet.
救护车
What happened to Bumblebee's voice-box?
大黄蜂的发声器是怎么回事？
It was... severely damaged in battle.
是在战斗中 严重受损
How?
怎么搞的？
How do you think?
你觉得呢？
Tragically, of course.
当然很惨
It happened at Tyger-Pax.
这发生在和平圣坛
Our brave scout was captured by Megatron's forces and interrogated.
我们勇敢的侦察兵被霸天虎抓住并遭严刑逼供
But he refused to provide intel.
不过他没有透露任何情报
And paid a grave price for his courage.
为此付出了惨重代价
Bumblebee was left for scrap.
大黄蜂几乎成为了一堆废铁
But Autobot troops found him and evacuated him to a triage facility.
不过汽车人部队找到了他 并送进了救护站
Where a field medic managed to stabilize his condition.
一个战地医生稳住了他的伤势
So, we owe Bumblebee's life to that field medic?
所以 大黄蜂的性命多亏了那位战地医生？
That's one way of looking at it, I suppose.
从某个角度来说可以这么认为
Though the medic... could have done better.
不过那个医生…本可以做得更好
Clear.
安全
I still don't know how you talked me into this.
天晓得我怎么会帮你这么干
You're worse than Miko.
你比神子还不安分
Yeah-yeah-yeah, I know.
好好好 我知道
Not every mission ends in a high-speed pursuit,
不是每次任务都需要高速追击
but without your...
但你要是不能…
Fine. I'll drop it.
好 我不说了
But if Optimus finds out, this was not my idea.
不过如果擎天柱发现了 别说这是我的主意
Signal's coming from over there.
信号来源就是那儿
And it's coming our way, fast!
正朝我们过来 还很快
Catch me if you can!
有本事就来抓我啊！
I'll get him!
我去抓住他！
Okay. You get him!
好吧 你去！
Sporting of you?
你在锻炼身体么？
You're not even gotta try and shoot up my tires?
不准备打爆我的轮胎么？
Bumblebee! Where is your famous horse-power?
大黄蜂 你那传说中的马力呢？
Show me some speed!
让我看看你的速度！
What is with the rent-a-car?!
那个老爷车是啥情况？
I'd stick around and do some doughnuts around you...
我也想陪你套会儿圈圈…
But I have a delivery to make.
不过我现在有货要送